You don't have to spend too long on
YouTube for videos to be coming up
everywhere
saying,
"If you want to make your first million,
if you want to make your first 10
million,
if I had to make 10 million again,
I'd do this.
How I made a million dollars."
Everything's about making millions
and becoming a
millionaire, and I think
if that's your goal, you
are fucked from the onset.
Before we made this video,
Declan behind the camera and I
were perusing YouTube to
look at what was currently trending.
Declan turns to me and he says,
"How many of the people in your course do
you think
are going to make it?" I said,
"What do you mean by making it?"
And what Declan
meant was making millions, to,
in a few years,
have a video like the ones in front
of us,
talking about how I made my first million.
And I said,
"I think a lot of people don't actually
understand what making it is."
The biggest issue we face, number one,
is something called the survivorship bias.
There could've been 1,000 personal
trainers that all went out and put out
content in 2014, and 10 years later,
I could just be the one in
1,000 anomaly that made it to the top.
Similarly to, I don't know
if many of you have seen this.
Have you heard of a guy called Derren
Brown? He's like a magician in the UK.
Basically,
he had a system where he could predict
what horse was going to win at
the horse race.
So you're watching the TV show.
This woman gets told,
"Bet on this horse," and it wins.
Another horse, it wins.
She gets to the sixth horse race,
and she's told to put all
of her money on this horse, so she does.
She scrapes together everything she can,
and she puts it on this horse.
He then says to her, "There
is no system." He started with, I think,
6,000 people.
So you've got 6,000 people in a six-horse
race.
Out of that, 5,000 people lose,
1,000 people are left.
Then in the next horse race,
let's say there's 10 horses.
900 people lose, 100 people are left.
Then there might be another five-horse
race, et cetera, and it whittles it down.
The woman who made it to the end
was just simply by chance the one person
that was lucky enough, through the odds,
to make it to the end, which gave
everyone else the illusion
that he had a system.
Another way we saw this, where it
was originally coined,
was in World War II,
planes would come back from battle,
and there'd be bullet holes in the wings.
And I can't remember the guy's name,
it was William something.
He pointed out, "Oh,
maybe we need more armor in those areas
that there are
bullet holes." And someone corrected him
and said, "No, we want armor in the places
there aren't bullet holes,
because the planes that
are coming home aren't showing
you where you need to put more armor.
The planes that didn't make it back would
show you that." The illusion was
created because only the information they
were getting was from planes that
made it, not the ones that didn't.
Similarly to so many things,
the things I'm saying on YouTube
and other people are saying,
we're only saying
because we survived this far.
The chances of you becoming a millionaire,
retiring your parents... Which,
may I just interrupt, what even is
a millionaire?
Do I have a million pounds in my account?
No.
Are my businesses worth a million pounds?
Well,
the way that you calculate what a business
is worth is mental.
In some cases, it's four
or five times the revenue of
that business.
So if you're turning over 200K a year,
you might only be making a 15% profit
margin, and you're telling the world, "Oh,
you know, I'm a millionaire," because...
Even the term millionaire is misconstrued.
So it's very difficult to listen to people
online, because the majority of them are
just lucky. Case in point, Bill Gates.
Do I like him?
No, I think he's a bit of a pleb. But
if Bill Gates was three or four years
older,
he would've gone through the education
system and would've been in full-time
employment when the first computer
was made.
If he was a little bit younger,
he would've been too young to get the time
away
from school to use the first computer.
The year that you're born
is a massive predictor of your success in
certain
realms. For instance, I'm what,
12 years older than you? Fucking hell.
My chance of booming on Facebook
were way bigger than yours,
because you would've
been like, two years old when I
was taking off on Facebook.
However,
my chances of being a successful YouTuber
at 35, especially
in the boom,
you would've been better off because you
would've been like, 15.
Not 15, but you know what I mean.
Even the month of the year that you're
born has a predictor to your sporting
ability.
Because for some people,
there's a month between them
and nearly a year of
development. So much of this is luck.
For me,
when video content started popping off,
let's say 2014, 2015,
2016, I was 27, which
is a pretty good age to be.
I'm old enough that people go,
"He's got a bit of experience,"
but I'm young enough
that someone's not like, "Hey,
get your granddad to get off the Facebook
Live." So we need to zoom out
and realize that the majority of the
people that you
see on YouTube, including myself, Chat
and Gas, we're in the top percent or the
top .1%. But that shouldn't matter,
and the reason for that is this.
Making it is not about reaching
that top percent.
Making it is about creating systems within
your business where if you
need more business, you can get it.
If you need more clients, you can get it.
And if you put a gun to my head today
and said, "James, could you get 10 or
100 more clients before the day closes?" I
could.
That's what you should have for yourself.
If you can imagine the happiness within
your professional life being like a table
propped up by many legs.
Work-life balance, which
is always going to be better
self-employed. If you work for someone,
they're going to take the maximum amount
of
your life for the least amount of money.
When you work for yourself,
you can kind of do what you want from a
day-to-day
basis,
and you might work for three hours
straight and go, "Do you know what?
I'm having a wank." You have a wank,
and then you're like, "Oh,
I kind of feel like
a nap." You have a nap,
you come back to doing work. I don't know.
Speaking from experience.
You have a cash flow perspective.
Even if you earn less money in your solo
venture as a sole trader,
you can still be happier. And again,
everyone seems to think there's a linear
path
between more money earned and happiness.
It's not true.
After about 60,000, 70,000 pounds a year,
we start to see a plateau with that.
Not to mention two things. One,
from a tax perspective, when people earn a
little bit less,
but they get to expense things,
they're happier.
Another thing we have is loss aversion.
The psychological pain of losing money
feels worse than not gaining it.
Therefore, tax bills kill people.
If you're working and earning 100K a year,
and you're giving 45% of it to the
government, it hurts.
If you then earned 70K a year
and gave a lot less to the
government, you'd be happier.
So you've got the money perspective.
Second of all, some things
that people massively underestimate
is that happiness
and pleasure are not the same things.
Happiness, dog walks, swim in the sea,
catching up with
friends, the finer things in life.
Pleasure, snorting coke,
partying with your mates,
going to a festival,
shagging strangers unprotected. Happiness,
pleasure.
You need to distinguish those,
because you can have a life of happiness
without
pleasure. Case in point, any of you
that have been to Asia, Indonesia, any of
those, you're like, "Whoa,
I'm surrounded by people.
This guy's only got one working flip-flop,
and he's happier than me.
This guy lives in a hammock,
and he's happier than me." Because they
have access to
happ-Happiness because they've got
friends, they've got their dog,
they've got
work, they've got meaning.
They just don't have access to Gucci
and business class and Dubai brunches.
They can survive being happy without
pleasure.
But if you make the mistake
that a lot of people do,
of mistaking happiness and
pleasure, you try
and fill your happiness cup with pleasure.
You go, "Oh,
I'm not feeling great about myself.
I'm going to go drinking." "I'm not
feeling great about myself.
I'm going to go do some rails of coke."
"I'm not feeling great about myself.
I'm going to go out
and get some unprotected sex." And
if you try and fill your
happiness cup with pleasure,
you end up with despair.
The point I'm trying to make is this.
So many people are in the prison of
high-paying,
earning jobs where they can't see
clearly that if they
were earning 200K a year,
and they took a pay cut to
100K,
and they went from a job they hated to a
job they liked, they'd be in a much
better position because they're fixated on
the money.
However, when you earn less,
you still have the equal access to
happiness.
You just do not have the equal access to
pleasure, like I've said before.
I've had periods in my life where I've
gone completely sober, and that is just a
decision for me to give up some pleasure,
drinking, partying, for
happiness.
And even those Saturday nights where I had
the itch to go out, when I
woke up on Sunday feeling good, it
was a net benefit.
And if any of you have the position in
your life to give up pleasure for
happiness,
please take it, even
if it means a pay cut.
And for so many of you just to be working
on that thing that you want, your passion
project, your hobby, whatever it is,
even if you're earning considerably less,
it's
just less handbags
and you might go back to economy for a few
flights, but you'll
be all right. Cool.
So we have the financial side of things.
We have the work-life balance side of
things.
Then we have the marketing side of things.
Marketing is a game.
Even right now with this video,
I'm playing a game.
I used to love playing games when I
was younger.
Everyone's like, "Oh,
you're a good marketer, James.
Is it because you did door-to-door sales
for years, or is it because you worked in
recruitment?" Truth is,
it's probably because I was a gamer.
I used to love playing games.
Always used to love getting high scores.
And have you ever noticed
that some people do better in video games
than they do in
real life?
They put more effort into their character
on Grand Theft Auto than they
do the character in real life.
They complete games,
but they never get anywhere in
life. And the reason for that
is objectives. So even think about this.
What I do in my line of work, this video,
my content, my mentorship, whatever it
is, oh, sly plug.
It's not about making people millionaires.
It's about giving people objectives.
Because when you play a video game,
when you're playing Grand Theft Auto,
all you
need to do is pause
and an objective will come up.
Go see this guy, go get that car,
go do this, go rob that bank,
whatever it is.
In life, there are no objectives.
Work hard, go to college, go to uni, get
a degree, work hard,
and in 50 years retire.
And if you die,
give money to the government.
If you buy a house,
If you sell the house,
give money to the government.
Anyway, what if making it
was just having a clear set of objectives
to do on
a daily basis? What
if making it isn't about seeing seven
zeros in your bank
account?
It's about being able to influence
that bank account whenever you want.
What if making it is waking up with
purpose?
What if making it is just waking up
and making your dreams come true instead
of
someone else's?
There's so many of these fucking bellends
online talking about
making millions. Alex Hormozi,
you look like one of the most miserable
fucking
people I've ever seen in my life. What
was the guy from One Direction?
Liam Payne.
All the money in the world.
It's such a leap to think
that seven zeros in
your bank account is going to make you
happy, when really, I believe good
objectives, good work-life balance,
and running your own books
is probably going to
make you a lot more happy. Making it,
you need to define it, because
if you don't
define it,
these fucking bellends on YouTube
are going to define it for you.
Your first million, your first 10 million.
Even this fucking pleb that's all over my
Instagram showing off about his fucking
private jets and guess what?
You can make it without ever even having
to visit
Dubai or having a Richard Mille fucking
watch.
I drove a Golf R up until the age of 34.
It was fine. It was great.
It made me really happy.
You're going to sit there and say, "Oh,
you've not made it
because you don't have a Ferrari." It's
bollocks. Back to Declan's point.
How many of these people in your
mentorship are really going to make it?
Well, if making it is to be a millionaire,
maybe not many.
Maybe some, but maybe not many. But
if we can reframe making it to actually
having
some kind of direction in your daily basis
and having some kind of ownership
over all the components in front of you
and treating all of it as a video game.
Social media, this video
that I'm ranting off the cuff.
I literally said, "Declan,
start recording." It's part of the game.
Because if I can get into people's minds,
move some things around, and realize they
are playing the wrong rule set for the
game, they can start playing it better.
Because if you set the goal as becoming a
millionaire or the most successful
person to ever do your job, chances
are you won't,
and you're going to feel fucking
deflated and depressed about it. But
if you instead just zone out and look at
what's in front of you
and realized what I do isn't even a
business
mentorship. I don't teach you
that much about business because guess
what?
You know how to do your fucking job.
If you're a fitness coach,
you know how to write programs.
If you're an editor,
you know how to edit content.
If you sell social housing,
you know how to sell social housing.
What you don't know
is all the things in front of it,
playing the game, content
creation, how to make good content,
how to package it, the title
and thumbnail for
this video,
and me looking miserable in the thumbnail.
How to get people's email addresses like
the links in my description that I'm
always writing. Oh,
30 days free business advice.
Email marketing campaigns,
whether they're automated or not.
I am happy.
I don't sound happy, do I?
Because I'm ranting. But I had to rant.
If I was just here
[email]